<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Matthew Allcock (neglectedness)</title><link>http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/categories/neglectedness.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 14:31:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Not all charity is equal</title><link>http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/posts/not-all-charity-is-equal/</link><dc:creator>Matthew Allcock</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;a href="http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/posts/effective-altruism/"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I have written about the importance of using an evidence-based approach to determine the most 
good we can do. One aspect of this is assessing the effectiveness of charities.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When buying a new phone, most people spend some time researching the best phone for their requirements and the best phone they can get for their budget.
This is clearly a good thing to do.
However, very few people consider how to make the most impact with their donations to charity. 
We are so careful with the money we spend on ourselves, but don't seem to take that same care over the money we use to do good.
Isn't that odd? If we were to buy a phone without looking to buy the best one, we risk being stuck with a clunky phone that cost us too much.
However, if we don't research how to make our donations go furthest, people whose lives could have been saved will die.
That is how it is. &lt;b&gt;It is not just a matter of getting more for your money, it is literally a matter of life or death&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/posts/not-all-charity-is-equal/#*"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;.
It is imperative that we start to research how to make the most difference with our donations.
In this post, I will discuss how we can determine the most effective charities.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/posts/not-all-charity-is-equal/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>charity</category><category>charity effectiveness</category><category>effective altruism</category><category>malaria</category><category>neglectedness</category><category>poverty</category><category>scale</category><category>suffering</category><category>tractability</category><guid>http://www.matthewallcock.co.uk/posts/not-all-charity-is-equal/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 20:10:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>